你在说什么
what are you talking about?
我跟你说
i'm telling you,
她不让我见他
she's hiding him from me.
她没有藏着他
she's not hiding him.
是吗
oh yeah?
每次我去见他
every time i go to see him,
她都说他刚安顿好
she tells me that he's just settled down.
你能怪她吗  是你没抓牢他
can you blame her? you dropped him.
不是我干的  他自己摔倒的
i did not drop him, he jumped.
摔倒?
jumped?
好吧  是他从我的怀里滑出去的
well, he wiggled out of my arms.
我已经道过歉了
i said i was sorry.
而且我有造成多少损失么
besides, how much damage could i possibly have done?
他摔了个大马趴
he fell, like, maybe two feet.
这事很常见的
stuff like that happens all the time.
我是说  当我还小时
i mean, i was dropped like, a dozen times
都被扔出过好多次
when i was a kid.
那就是原因所在
well, that explains a lot.
你在介意什么  你甚至都不喜欢小孩子
why do you even care? you don't even like kids.
这是原则问题
it's the principle of the thing.
每个人都能抱他  我为什么就不行
everybody else gets to hold him. why shouldn't i?
中校...
colonel...
我们收到新信号
we've got a new contact.
像是一艘战舰
looks like a ship.
相距多远
how far out?
已进入轨道内
it's in orbit.
可是  我们怎么没有侦测到它
well, how come we didn't detect it?
我不清楚
i don't know.
我们甚至没有探测到超空间窗口
we didn't even detect a hyperspace window.
它就这么突然冒出来了
it just appeared out of nowhere.
稍等  我们收到敌我识别信号了
hang on a second, we're getting i.f.f.
是代达罗斯号
it's the daedalus.
代达罗斯号?  怎么可能?
the  daedalus? how can that be?
他们正在返回地球
they're on their way back to earth.
是的  他们应该在路上
well, they were. they were supposed to be.
打开一个频道
open up a channel.
代达罗斯号  这里是亚特兰蒂斯  请接入
daedalus, this is atlantis, please come in.
代达罗斯号  请回复
daedalus, please respond.
他们不会回复的
they're not going to answer.
为什么不会?
why not?
我没发现任何生命信号
because i'm not reading any lifesigns.
你想告诉我什么  罗德尼
what are you telling me, rodney,
这飞船自己控制飞行?
this thing flew here by itself?
我不知道它是怎样到这里的
i don't know how they got here,
但是那上面空无一人
but there's no one on board.
至少是没一个活人
at least, no one alive.
中校  我们刚从星门指挥部
colonel, we just got confirmation
得到确认消息
from stargate command.
代达罗斯号正在银河中
the  daedalus is in the milky way,
按照原定计划
on course and on schedule.
有望在两天内到达地球
they expect to reach earth within two days.
明白
understood.
看来那不是代达罗斯号
so that's not the  daedalus, then.
好吧...
well...
除非它有分身之术
not unless it can be in two places at once.
也许是阿波罗号  或者是其他的飞船
perhaps the  apollo, or one of your other ships...
那它就不会发送代达罗斯号的敌我识别信号
they wouldn't be sending  daedalus i.f.f.,
更何况也无法解释它是如何到这的
plus it doesn't explain how they got here,
以及为何侦测不到生命信号
or why we're not picking up lifesign readings.
那好吧
all right,
我们凑近点看看
i'm taking us in for a closer look.
你看见那个没?
wow, you see that?
有许多焦灼痕迹
yeah, some scorch marks.
你认为是武器攻击的?
you think weaponsfire?
不管它经历过什么
well, wherever she's been,
肯定是历尽艰险
she's been through some pretty hard times.
那是什么
what's that?
我收到了能量读数
i'm picking up an energy reading.
是来自那飞船的
it's coming from the ship.
有危险吗
is it dangerous?
我不认为有
i don't think so,
但我不清楚是什么引起的
but i have no idea what's causing it.
你能打开停泊舱门吗?
can you get the bay doors open?
应该没问题
if the ship's command systems
只要飞船的控制系统
are as familiar as the rest of it,
和其他系统一样简单
it shouldn't be a problem.
不是f302型
no f-302s,
但是有一个小飞船
but there's a jumper.
你确定里面没人吗
you sure there's no one else inside?
目前为止是的
as far as i can tell.
好的  我们进去
all right, we're going in.
为什么这里面这么冷
why is it so cold in here?
飞船的运作要靠能源
the ship's operating on emergency power.
有些系统根本没有启动
some of the systems are barely registering.
除了那个奇怪的能量源
except for the whole weird energy thing.
说的对
that's right.
有什么办法吗
can you do something about it?
这里冻死了
it's freezing in here.
当然  我需要去下工程舱
oh, sure, i just have to get to engineering.
你和若楠一起
you and ronon are together.
泰勒  你和我去舰桥看看
teyla, you and i are going to check out the bridge.
有任何发现就用无线电联系我
radio me if you find anything.
这里空无一人...
no bodies in here.
中校...
colonel...
这是代达罗斯号  没错
it's the  daedalus , all right.
麦凯  是你弄的吗
mckay, is that you?
当然了  还会是谁?
of course it was me. who else would it be?
难道你认为这里有鬼还是什么
you think we've got a ghost on board or something?
不要乱动任何东西!
will you please not touch anything!
我们的情况如何
what's our status?
我恢复了飞船的大部分基础能量
i've restored basic power to most of the ship.
飞船立刻就会恢复能源
it should be warming up any second now.
很好
good.
检查那个能量读数
check on that energy reading.
看看到底是什么意思
try to figure out what it is, all right?
我正在查
i'm on it.
中校...
colonel...
飞船日志  最后一次记录
ship's log, last entry.
准备基本完毕
preparations are almost complete.
已经传送下最后的补给
we've beamed down the last of our supplies,
以及任何我们可能需要的装备
and any equipment we think might be useful.
我会自己携带最后的f302
i'll be taking the last of the f-302s down myself.
当然  我们没有时间
of course, we haven't had time
对行星表面进行详细调查
to do a proper survey of the planet's surface,
但是似乎相当适合居住
but it seems habitable enough.
淡水充足  土壤肥沃
plenty of fresh water, arable soil,
与地球十分相似
not that different from our own.
我意识到我们被援救的机会微乎其微
i realize our chance of rescue is slim,
但是事实很明显
but it's become obvious
我们已别无选择
that we no longer have a choice.
我是索博上校  代达罗斯号指挥官
this is colonel sobol, commander of the  daedalus ,
信号终止
signing off.
你认识她?
do you recognize her?
我以前从未见过她
i've never seen her before in my life.
看来他们弃船了
well, it appears as if they abandoned ship.
对
yeah.
可是到底为什么
the question is, why?
我来看下之前的记录
i'll check previous entries.
天哪  这飞船跟被大卸八块似的
man, this ship has been through the wringer.
没有超空间引擎
no hyperdrive,
亚空间通信装备损坏得无法修复
subspace communications are all damaged beyond repair,
护盾不堪一击
the shields are virtually depleted...
那是什么
what is it?
是能量读数
it's the energy reading.
它在脉冲
it's spiking.
谢帕德  请接入
sheppard, come in.
请讲
go ahead.
情况不妙
something's happening.
能量读数正高出图表
the energy reading, it's going off the charts.
做点什么  把它关掉
do something. turn it off.
我不知道怎么关掉
i don't know how.
它不是从任何主系统发出的
look, it's not coming from any of the main systems.
谢帕徳中校  这里是亚特兰蒂斯
colonel sheppard, this is atlantis.
我们收到巨大的能量信号
we're picking up some kind of power surge
是从飞船上发出的
coming from the ship.
是的  我们注意到了
yeah, we noticed it.
我们正试着自己把它找出来
we're trying to check it out ourselves.
能量等级正不断抬升
the levels are still rising.
中校  需要我们派出另一艘飞船支援吗
colonel, should we send another jumper to assist?
待命
stand by.
好吧  我们开始撤离
all right, that's our cue to leave.
所有人回到飞船内
everyone, back in the jumper.
麦凯  那他妈的是什么
mckay, what the hell was that?
我不知道  但是...
i have no idea, but...
能量读数恢复初始了
the energy reading's gone back down the way it was.
亚特兰蒂斯   发现任何异常迹象吗
atlantis, you reading anything unusual?
亚特兰蒂斯  请接入
atlantis, come in.
亚特兰蒂斯  收得到信号吗
atlantis, do you read?
谢帕徳中校  收到信号吗
colonel sheppard, do you read?
代达罗斯号  请回复  这里是亚特兰蒂斯
daedalus , this is atlantis, please respond.
到底发生什么了
what the hell's going on?
我不知道
i don't know.
上一刻他们还在
one moment they were there,
下一刻就消失了
the next minute, they were gone.
罗德尼?
rodney?
我们的通讯有问题
i'm having problems with communications.
我无法与亚特兰蒂斯号取得联系
i can't reach atlantis.
稍等
wait a second.
这不对劲啊
that can't be right.
什么
what?
我在屏幕上看不到任何城市
i'm not seeing the city on any of my screens.
你在说什么
what are you talking about?
我刚进行了传感器扫描
i just did a sensor sweep,
发现下面只有一片汪洋大海
and there's nothing down there but ocean.
也许他们隐蔽起来了
well, maybe they cloaked.
他们不可能不通知我们一声啊
well, they wouldn't have done that without telling us.
我也不知道
well, i don't know,
也许那里有一艘幽灵飞船
maybe there's a wraith ship in the area.
我什么都没发现
i'm not reading anything.
我们还是在同一个星球上吗
are we certain it's the same planet?
也许是能量爆发使我们的位置偏移了
perhaps the energy burst shifted our position.
不会  根据我们的仪器检测
no, according to our instruments,
我们根本没有动
we haven't moved at all.
那你要让我怎么想  罗德尼
what do you want me to believe, rodney?
亚特兰蒂斯就这么消失了?
that atlantis just disappeared?
听着  我不知道
look, i don't know.
给我点时间  我会弄明白的  好吗
just give me a second, i'll figure it out, all right?
同时  我会设法定位出
in the meantime, i've managed to localize
能量读取的来源
the source of the energy reading.
是来自于9号甲板的一个舱位
it's coming from a hold on deck 9.
好吧  继续和亚特兰蒂斯联系
all right, keep trying to reach atlantis.
我们去看一下
we'll check it out.
谢帕德  我想我发现了什么
sheppard, i think i've got something.
是刚才那次闪光的辐射残余
it's the residual radiation from the flash.
和打开超空间飞行窗口的情况有些类似
it's similar to what happens when you open a hyperspace window,
但又有所不同
but different enough
因为传感器不会自动加速的
that the sensors wouldn't have picked it up automatically.
那是什么意思
what the hell does that mean?
我想我们经历的是一种新的推进方式
i think we're looking at a new kind of drive.
我记得你说过我们根本没有移动过
i thought you said we didn't go anywhere.
我们是没有
we didn't.
至少从飞船的导航系统来看是没有
at least not according to the ship's navigational systems.
那么是一次故障性推进?
so, a malfunctioning drive?
或许吧
maybe.
稍等下
just hang on.
天啊  谢帕德
oh, my god, sheppard--
镇定点  罗德尼
stand by, rodney.
不  你没明白  我知道怎么回事了
no, you don't understand, i know what it is.
听着  那些辐射残余
look, the residual radiation.
正是我们从外空间
it's exactly what we recorded
两次到达亚特兰蒂斯
when my double arrived on atlantis
所记录的能源
from an alternate reality.
真不敢相信我以前没有注意到
i can't believe i didn't see this before.
谢帕德
sheppard, hey.
这的确是一次推进
it's a drive all right,
但并没有在空间里进行
but it didn't move us through space.
我想我们进入的是一个平行宇宙
i think it's moved us into a parallel universe.
这就可以解释很多事情了
that would explain a lot of things.
他们死了有多久了
how long have they been dead for?
这里就像一个储肉柜
this place was like a meat locker.
他们可能已经这样保存了几个月了
they could've been preserved like this for months.
他们看起来可真像我们
they look just like us.
那是因为就是我们
that's because they are us--
另一个时空的我们
the alternate reality versions of us.
我感觉就像有人走进了我们的墓地
i feel like someone just walked over my grave.
放松  一切都很好
take it easy. everything's fine.
不不  这很糟
oh, no, no, no, this is very bad.
什么
what?
这个手写板是另一个麦凯的
this tablet belonged to the other mckay.
他们也不是原来这里的船员
they weren't part of the original crew.
他们像我们一样来到这
they came here just like us.
听着  亚特兰蒂斯上空的轨道上
look, a ship appeared in orbit
出现了一艘飞船
above their atlantis,
他们是上来查看的
they came to check it out.
这就可以解释
that would explain
港口的另一艘飞船
the other jumper in the bay.
这艘飞船进入了另一个时空
the ship jumped to another reality,
而且他们被困在那  无法返航
and they were stuck, they couldn't get back.
听着  到最后
look, eventually
他们的补给耗光了
their supplies ran out,
他们就...
and they...
好了  好了  谜底揭开了
all right, all right, mystery solved.
我们得行动了
let's move on.
你没意识到这代表什么吗
don't you realize what this means?
他们就是我们  而且他们失败了
they were us, and they failed.
他们可不是我们
well, they're not us.
我们还活的好好的
we're still alive.
走吧
let's go.
答案就在这附近
the answer's in here somewhere.
可以把这的系统启动吗
can you power up the systems?
可以  稍等一下
uh... yeah, just hold on.
好了
all right...
好吧  开始了
all right, that's a start.
那后面是什么
what's behind here?
问的好
that's a good question.
我想这就是我们变换时空的推进装置
i'm guessing that's our alternate reality drive.
你能弄明白如何操控它吗
can you figure out how to control it?
唐突的说  我不能
offhand, i'd say no.
这是另一个麦凯一直试图弄明白的
that's what the other mckay was trying to do,
而且他用了...  好几周的时间
and he had... weeks.
罗德尼
rodney...
好吧
fine.
我从他的研究成果开始
i'll start with his research.
至少我们在开头领先了
it'll at least give us a head start.
这就好多了
that's better.
我们去找些补给
we're going to go look for supplies.
你认为另一个时空的我们
you don't think the other us
没有试过吗
wouldn't have already tried that?
干活去
get to work.
有发现吗
did you find anything?
没有  除非你知道这东西怎么吃
not unless you know a way to cook this.
也许我们应该考虑降落到星球上
perhaps we should consider going down to the planet
去搜集补给
to collect supplies.
谢帕德说这太冒险了
sheppard says it's too risky.
推进或许会再次发生
the drive could kick in,
飞船会自行起飞
and the ship could take off without us.
那我们就被困在这了
then we'd be stuck here.
我们发现的那些自己
the others that we found...
你觉得他们的生活和我们很相似吗
do you think their lives were very similar to ours?
谁在乎这个
who cares?
你怎么能这么说
how can you say that?
我们以前见过更多的自己
we've seen our doubles before.
那是人造的复制品
replicator-manufactured copies.
但他们是真正的人类  有真正的生命
these were real people, with real lives.
我忍不住去想
i can't help but wondering
会是谁在亚特兰蒂斯
who might still be waiting for her
等待她归来
back on her atlantis.
你意思是  她也有个儿子?
do you mean, did she also have a son?
这念头刚刚一闪而过
the thought had crossed my mind.
听着
look...
我已经听麦凯讲过这种事情了
i've heard mckay talk about this stuff before,
照这么假设的话
and supposedly,
有百万个不同的时空
there's a million different realities out there,
每一个时空都有可能出现各种变化
with every possible variation.
也就是说
which also means
会有百万个不同的图门
there's a million different torrens.
那么你还会去担心他们每一个人吗
you going to worry about every one of them?
不会
no.
担心一个就已经够麻烦了
it's difficult enough worrying about one.
我想也是
i'll bet it is.
来吧
come on.
防爆门怎么关上了
why is the blast door closed?
记得吗  有辐射残余
hello? residual radiation?
哦对
oh, right.
你有什么进展了吗
have you made any progress?
事实上
as a matter of fact,
是的  我们有了
yes, we have.
我们?
we?
我和另一个麦凯
me and the other mckay,
而他  毫无惊讶地也是个天才
who, unsurprisingly, is a genius.
不仅如此
not only that,
而且这个推进装置看来是由
but it looks like the drive was created
最初船上的那个麦凯制造的
by yet another mckay from the original reality.
为什么这么说
what makes you say that?
因为我发现有某种
well, there's a certain, um,
我所熟识的精巧设计
elegance to the design that i recognize.
我肯定当船员弃船逃生的时候
i'm sure that's what the crew was saying
他们也是这么说的
when they abandoned ship.
不可否认这里确实有些问题
well, admittedly there are problems,
但仍然算是一项伟大的发明
but it is still a monumental achievement.
那么我们该怎么做
so, what do we do?
我们可以直接让它反向运行吗
can we just throw this thing in reverse?
是啊  比那还要再复杂些
uh, yeah, it's a little more complicated than that.
第一个问题是导航装置
the first problem is navigation.
他们开发了一种坐标系统
they've developed a coordinate system
来区分不同的时空
to identify the various realities
以使他们可以来去自由
and allow them to get back,
但很明显这不管用
but obviously that didn't work.
显而易见
obviously.
这还不是让我烦心的
that's not what bothers me.
这有点让我烦心了
well, it kind of bothers me.
是能源系统
it's power generation,
从一个时空向另一个时空跃迁
and jumping from one reality to another
需要巨大的能量
requires massive amounts of power.
我们说的可是零点装置级别的
we're talking zpm levels here.
很明显他们没有足够的能量来回传着玩
obviously they didn't have one of those rattling around,
所以他们造了一种电容器
so they created a capacitor
来不断地从亚空间抽取能量
that's constantly drawing power from subspace.
看起来似乎能量快充满了
and it looks like it's almost charged.
你罗嗦了这么多  是不是就为了告诉我
is this your long-winded way of telling me
你关不上它
you just can't turn it off?
联想一下  就像开着水龙头向桶里灌水
think of it like a tap, pouring water into a bucket.
当水桶满了的时候  动力系统就会运行
when the bucket is full, the drive engages,
只是这个特殊的水龙头好像没有阀门
except this particular tap has no valve.
像是一种严重的设计失误
that seems like a pretty serious design flaw,
你觉得不是吗
don't you think?
没错
exactly.
这让我觉得他们是在干扰它
which leads me to believe they were tampering with it,
不要让它继续徒然的吸取能量了
in a vain attempt to generate more power.
我想他们也从自己不妙的处境看出来了
as they got further and further from their own reality,
他们必须要返航
i guess they figured they'd need it to get back.
然后我们好了
and here we go.
好吧
okay.
我们这是在哪
where are we?
别看我
oh, don't look at me.
我根本没来得及在主系统的控制面板上
i haven't had time to route the main systems
设定路线呢
to these control panels.
我完全是盲目传到这的
i'm flying blind down here.
若楠  泰勒  到舰桥来见我
ronon, teyla, meet me at the bridge.
马上出发
on our way.
继续努力  罗德尼
keep it up, rodney.
中校  亚特兰蒂斯回来了
colonel, atlantis is back.
我正用传感器接收他们
i'm picking them up on the sensors.
你知道这玩意怎么弄
you know how to work this stuff?
上次代达罗斯号还在运行轨道上时
the last time the daedalus was in orbit,
马克斯少校慷慨地
major marks generously offered
给了我们俩一些基础培训
to give both of us some preliminary training.
我那时很忙
i was busy.
亚特兰蒂斯  我是谢帕德  请讲
atlantis, this is sheppard, come in.
亚特兰蒂斯  能听到吗
atlantis, do you read?
亚特兰蒂斯  我是谢帕德  请讲
atlantis, this is sheppard, come in.
可能他们已经有谢帕德了
maybe they already have a sheppard.
罗德尼  我们随机回到自己的世界
rodney, what are the odds of us
的几率会有多大
randomly jumping back into our own reality?
机会微乎其微
i'd say slim to none.
我查到轨道上还有一艘飞船
i'm detecting another ship in orbit.
怎么样的
what kind?
我看看能不能显示到屏幕上
i'll see if i can pull it up on screen.
我认不出来
i don't recognize it.
那是什么
what's that?
你认识吗
you know it?
不
no.
中校  我想
colonel, i believe
这艘船在准备武器
the ship is powering weapons.
我们护盾的情况怎么样
what's our shield status?
最差状态
minimal.
它在攻击亚特兰蒂斯
it's firing on atlantis.
它的护盾能量在消减
the city's shields are failing.
罗德尼  燃料够发动阿斯加德光束吗
rodney, do we have enough juice to power up the asgard beam?
也许
maybe.
你可以打上两枪  怎么了
you might be able to get a couple of shots off. why?
有异族飞船在攻击亚特兰蒂斯
there's some alien ship attacking atlantis.
然后呢
so?
你什么意思  那是亚特兰蒂斯
what do you mean, "so?" it's atlantis!
但那不是我们的亚特兰蒂斯
it's not our atlantis.
我们都不知道那上面有谁
we have no idea who's down there.
我们还是别管闲事
look, we should just stay out of it.
如果我们不帮忙  亚特兰蒂斯就毁了
if we do not intervene, the city will be destroyed.
我们需要帮助
yeah, we need help.
直觉告诉我  我们最好
my gut tells me we're better off
帮那星球上的人一把
going with the people on that planet
管那上面是谁
than whoever's on that ship.
希望你是对的
i hope you're right.
我也希望
yeah, well, me too.
那船受到损坏
the ship's been damaged.
它停止攻击了
it's stopped firing.
希望我们破坏了它的主要武器
hopefully we took out its main weapons.
等等  不对劲
wait, something's happening.
他们派出小飞船了
they're launching fighters.
若楠...
ronon...
你有机会的时候应该要抓紧
you should've took marks up when you had the chance.
你必须现学现卖
now you'll have to learn fast.
电磁轨道炮瞄准系统
rail-gun targeting systems.
按钮在右边
button's on the right.
控制  雷达  跟踪
control, radar, tracking,
然后目标确认
and target acquisition,
按红按钮发射
use the red button to fire.
见鬼  发生了什么
what the hell was that?
我们被攻击了
we're under attack.
能不能把超光速推进器弄好
any chance of getting that hyperdrive back online?
不行  已经完全损坏了
no, it's completely shot!
我告诉过你了
i already told you that!
真是好啊
great.
他们人太多了
there's too many of them.
我坚持不了了
i can't do this.
继续
keep trying!
我们失去了亚光速
we've lost sublight.
船体有裂缝了
we have a hull breach.
空气在流失
we're venting atmosphere.
我不知道该怎么办了
i don't know what to do.
关闭损坏区域
seal off damaged areas.
暂时应该没问题
we should be okay for the moment.
要我就不会那么肯定
i wouldn't be so sure about that.
谢帕德  我有个主意
sheppard, i have an idea!
说来听听
let's hear it.
我建立了新协议
i've set up a few protocols
能提高变换时空推进器
that should increase the efficiency
的工作效率
of the alternate reality drive.
如果可以  我们可以马上跃迁到其他时空
if i enable them, we might be able jump sooner.
什么  跃迁到其他时空
what, jump to the next universe?
完全正确
exactly!
但做了就无法回头了
but if i do this, i can't undo it!
我们就会跃迁得越来越快
i mean, we'll just start jumping faster and faster!
就这么做
do it.
成功了
it worked.
我们在哪儿
where are we?
我们有麻烦了
we have a problem.
船体的温度在急速上升
temperature in the hull is rising rapidly.
这是什么鬼东西
what the hell is this?
根据这些数据显示
according to these readings,
我们离太阳外沿
we're less than two million kilometers
不到两百万公里
from the surface of the sun.
我觉得我们总是跃迁到不同时空
i thought we always jumped to the same place
的同一个地方
in every reality.
我也这么想
as did i.
舱体温度到达危险边缘了
hull temperature is approaching critical.
如果不能重新展开护盾
if we do not restore shields...
我们要被烤焦了
we're going to burn.
你确定?
are you sure about this?
这不是我们想象出来的  罗德尼
well, we're not imagining it, rodney.
我把传感器送下去
let me transfer the sensors down to the station.
那至少我能...
then at least i can...
这确实不是你们想象出来的
well, you're definitely not imagining that.
谢谢你的信任
thanks for the vote of confidence.
我不明白
i don't understand it.
我们总到在不同时空的相同地点
we always jump to the same relative position in space.
除非...
unless...
除非什么
unless what?
你说当你在未来时
you said when you went to the future,
看到太阳扩张成红色巨球记得吗
you saw our sun expanding into a red giant, remember?
你是说我们跨越时间了?
what are you saying, we're jumping through time now?
不不不不
no, no, no, no, no,
但也许在我们时空的里终要发生的
but maybe what eventually happens in our reality
就是现在这里已经发生的  只是快很多
is happening in this one, only much sooner.
不是我们到太阳这里
we didn't go to the sun.
是太阳朝着我们来了
the sun came to us.
这对我们有什么帮助
so how does this help us?
我...我不知道
i-i don't know.
我只是觉得很有意思
i just, i found it interesting.
罗德尼  有意思的是
what's interesting, rodney,
想个法子离开这里  免得被烤焦
is a way out of this without getting fried,
比如修好亚光速器
like getting sublight back on,
那我们就能离开这鬼地方了
so we can get the hell out of here.
实际上  我觉得我们最好
actually, i think our best bet
还是尽可能转移能量到护盾上
is just to transfer as much power as we can to the shields,
然后等着下一次跃迁
and ride it out till the next jump.
要多久
when does that happen?
电容的充电时间差别很大
well, the time the capacitor takes to charge is different
因为我定了新协议
now that i've enacted those new protocols.
你知道...
you know, um...
我不知道
i have no idea.
你这根本不是计划  罗德尼
you're not exactly selling the plan, rodney.
我也不知道修好亚光速器
i have no idea how long it would take me
要花多长时间
to fix the sublights either!
我需要进行诊断
look, i've got to run a diagnostic,
理论上  传递能量给护盾
but theoretically, transferring power to the shields
更简单一些
should be relatively easy.
好吧  我们怎么做
all right, what do we do?
首先我要你们到工程舱
the first i need you to do is head down to engineering.
走吧
let's go.
好了  我们到了
all right, we're here.
怎么做
what do we do?
把所有能量都调到
you need to kill all power
"非必要"档
to non-essential decks.
这样就要打开
which means you're going to have to access
主控干预
the main administrative interface.
然后会显示一串
that should bring up a list
可用的多余指令
of all available override commands.
弄好了
got it.
好
okay.
选"生命支持控制"
so choose the command for life support.
你们需要一级一级
you'll have to designate the decks
设定
one by one.
已经全部设定完毕
i think that's all of them.
该死
damn it.
没有提供我预料中足够的能量
that didn't buy us nearly as much power as i would have thought.
一定还有什么疏忽了
well, there's got to be something else.
对...
right, um...
船有辅助能量模块
all right, look, the ship has auxiliary power modules
供应主要系统
for most of the main systems.
很可能能量都耗尽了
most likely they're depleted,
但如果没有
but if not, well,
也许能再给我们点能量
it might buy us a little more juice.
那就这样吧
well, there you go.
那是什么
what the hell was that?
枪战?
was it gunfire?
若楠在哪儿
where's ronon?
你继续
keep working.
集中注意  罗德尼
stay focused, rodney.
告诉我接下去怎么做
tell me what to do next.
好的
all right.
你还好吗
you okay?
嗯
yeah.
他从哪儿冒出来的
where the hell did he come from?
你看
check it out.
这是在异族飞船上看到的符号
it's the symbol that was on the alien ship.
他是怎么上来的
how'd he get onboard?
记得吗  他们朝我们撞上来
you know, they crashed into us,
穿过我们的船体
penetrated our hull, remember?
这么说他是故意的?
think he did it on purpose?
问得好
that's a good question.
我来试试
let me try that--
好了
that's it.
差不多都设置完毕了
that's all of them.
我得去帮谢帕德中校和若楠了
i must go help colonel sheppard and ronon.
罗德尼  你自己小心了
good luck, rodney.
不  不  不  不够哇
no, no, no, no, no, it's not enough!
什么意思
what do you mean?
没有亚光速  我们的在轨道在向太阳收缩
without sublights, our orbit is decaying,
这就意味这更多的辐射会冲进我们的护盾
which means more radiation slamming into the shields.
变换时空的推进器也才充了70%左右
the alternate reality drive is only charged to 70% percent.
等不到充完  我们的护盾就先崩溃了
which means it'll never make 100 before the shields fail.
那我们该怎么办
well, what do we do?
我们没有能源了
we have no more power.
让我想想
j-just... give me a second.
罗德尼  谢帕德和若楠现在受到攻击了
rodney, colonel sheppard and ronon are under attack.
我知道了  我知道了
all right, i got it, i got it.
关闭护盾
drop the shields.
什么
what?
关闭护盾
drop the shields,
我会尽量把所有的能源都传输到推进器
i will transfer all available power to the drive.
希望足够我们进行下一次跃迁
hopefully it'll be enough to induce a jump.
希望?
hopefully?
这是我们唯一的办法了
it is our only option,
我们越争论一分
and every second we argue about it,
成功的机会就少一分
is less of a chance it's going to work!
好吧
very well.
关闭护盾
dropping shields.
船体温度超过安全指数了
hull temperature is passing critical.
现在  把能源都转到推进器上
okay, transferring power to the drive now.
不  不  不
oh, no, no, no, no, no.
怎么了
what is it?
还是不够啊  只有98%
it's not enough. it's only 98%!
罗德尼  船体开始损毁了
rodney, the hull is beginning to deteriorate.
加把劲啊  加把劲
come on, come on!
就现在  谢帕德  我们要跃迁了
that's it! sheppard, we're jumping!
干得好  罗德尼
nice work, rodney.
你不会想这么早夸我的
uh, you may want to hold off on the congratulations.
又怎么了
now what?
我好像使推进器超负荷了
i think i've overtaxed the drive.
虽然还没有爆炸
look, it's not completely blown, but
我们还有几次跃迁  但它已经快撑不住了
we've only a handful of jumps before it's burned out.
好吧  然后会怎样
all right, then what happens?
如果到那时候  我们还不知道如何返回的话
if we haven't found our way back by then,
我们就再也回不去了
we will be stranded forever.
这星球怎么了
what happened to the planet?
罗德尼认为  在这一时空里
rodney believes that in this reality,
它被一股或许是几百万年前的冲击力破坏了
it was destroyed by an impact,possibly millions of years ago.
留下了这一片星场
all that remains is this asteroid field.
来  我有些新发现了
all right, i think i got something.
其实就一直都在那
in fact, it was staring me in the face the whole time.
是我之前专注于躲避危险而没有注意到
i was just too busy trying to avoid imminent death to notice it.
你说的是什么
what are you talking about?
是我的错  老是盯着导航系统不放
see, my mistake was focusing on the navigation system.
我早该知道的  这法子没用
i should've known that was never going to work.
然后呢
so, what, then?
多谢多维数学的奇妙特性
so in spectacular feat of multi-dimensional mathematics,
我找到个办法  使我们的飞船
i've discovered a way to send the ship back
既能够原路返回
along the path it's previously traveled
又能够绕开导航系统
bypassing the navigation system altogether.
等一下
wait a minute.
你的意思是把这东西反向运行?
you're talking about putting this thing in reverse?
完全正确
exactly.
我2个小时前就这么说过了
i just suggested that two hours ago.
我之前是根本没想过嘛
and naturally,i dismissed it out of hand,
接着我又意识到  包括最初的设计者
but then i realized that, including the original designer,
不是一个  已经是有两个版本的我
not one, but two versions of myself
都没办法搞定这东西了
have failed to make this thing work.
我不能按我的模式来思考
i had to think not like me.
必须要跳出我的模式思考
i had to think the opposite of me.
当局者迷  旁观者清
doesn't get more opposite than you.
我把它理解成夸奖我了
i'll take that as a compliment.
那我们是回得去还是回不去
so can we get back or not?
不完全是
well, not directly.
要计算出
it's impossible to calculate
我们的起点和现在位置的相对方位
the relative position of our original starting point
是有点不太可能的
from where we are now,
但是可以追踪我们之前的脚步
but we can retrace our steps,
把每一个时空轮流转一遍
passing through each reality in turn
直到找到正确的那个
until we reach the right one.
有点小问题  罗德尼
slight problem, rodney.
我们不太可能活着离开这些时空的
we barely got out of those realities alive.
如果我们不修复护盾
if we do no restore the shields,
太阳的辐射就会置我们于死地
the radiation from the red giant will kill us.
那倒不一定
not necessarily.
我们知道
we let the ship carry us
飞船能够用它的动量载我们
in its momentum in real space
从这个时空到下一个
from one reality to the next.
我们现在亚光速引擎也许不能用了
now, we may not have sublight engines,
但我们至少还有起飞加速器
but we do have maneuvering thrusters.
只要沿着正确的轨道
you know, one long continuous burn
从现在起直到下一个跃迁
along the right trajectory,
引擎长时间持续运转
from now until the next jump
应该还是足够我们
should be enough to allow us to establish a higher,
在太阳附近建立一个更稳定的轨道
more stable orbit around the sun.
从而就能不受辐射影响?
so the radiation will not affect us?
我没想那么多
well, i wouldn't go that far,
但至少可以...避免不死吧?
but still, it'll be... not quite as deadly?
好了
okay.
就是这样
that's it.
我们就这样子办好了
course is already plotted.
那这些异族家伙呢
what about those alien dudes?
他知道是我们朝他们开枪的
they're know we're the ones that shot at them.
说不定他们到时候就走了
maybe they'll be gone.
顾不上他们了
i wouldn't count on it.
在每个时空
time is passing at the same rate
时间的流逝还是按照相同比率的
in each of the realities, which means...
这就说明了...不会那么久啦
it hasn't been that long.
要搞定那些异族的
to get past those aliens,
我们还是需要有亚光速引擎
we're going to need sublight engines,
我得去尽快修好它
and i'm going to need to fix them in time.
等一下  你不是说都不知道是什么毛病吗
wait, wait, but you said you don't know what's wrong with those.
我是还没机会去看过啊
i haven't had a chance to check it out.
很遗憾  我又没有三头六臂
i'm sorry i can't do 10 things at once.
我都说了
i already told you,
推进器马上就撑不住了的
the drive is going to burn out,soon.
我们总得采取点行动吧
we have to do something.
说不定下个时空会更糟
who's to say the next reality won't be even worse?
好了
all right,
推进器的所有设置更改完毕
all the modifications to the drive are in place.
开始!
here we go.
成功了
it worked.
你办到了  罗德尼
you did it, rodney.
那好吧
all right,
我现在过去引擎那边了
i'm going to head up to engineering,
去检查下亚光速器
get to work on the sublights.
现在情况怎样
what's our status?
机身温度上升
hull temperature is rising,
但不如以前那么快
but not as rapidly as it did before.
我想应该没问题
i think we'll be okay.
已经都烤了这么长时间了
so much for the frying pan.
但愿能够经得起高温
let's hope we make it through the fire.
进展如何
how is it coming?
不太好
ah, it's not good.
主要系统的温度都太高了
the main systems are completely fried.
我得架个辅助通道
i'll have to do a full bypass.
我能帮忙么
can i be of assistance?
可能不行
i doubt it.
噢  该死的
oh, jeez!
搞什么
what the...
多谢
thanks.
或许可以单独诊断一下辅助系统
perhaps a separate diagnostic of the auxiliary system might be useful.
我试试
uh, sure.
谢谢你  罗德尼
i wanted to thank you, rodney.
为什么
for what?
因为你不放弃
for not giving up.
噢  我知道是怎么回事了
oh, i know what this is.
这是你回来后的第一个任务
it's your first mission back.
放心  我不会让它变成你的最后一个
look, i am not about to let it be your last, okay?
不  这正是我所担心的
oh, no, that's what i was afraid of.
那是什么
what is it?
推进器能量充得快了许多
the drive's charging a lot faster now.
谢帕德
sheppard...
看来马上要开始下一次跃迁
looks like the next jump's going to happen
比我们料想得快多了
a lot sooner than we thought.
亚光速引擎怎样了
how's it coming with the sublight engine?
还要几分钟
i'm going to need a few minutes.
我们还能有几分钟吗
do we have a few more minutes?
我很怀疑
i doubt it.
电磁轨道炮又派上用场了
all right, let's split rail gun positions.
我在前  你断后
i'll take forward, you take aft.
你觉得这样有用么
you really think that'll make a difference?
没有护盾  也许没什么用
without shields, probably not,
但我们没得选了
but we don't have much of a choice.
异族的飞船在哪
where's the alien ship?
不太清楚
i'm not sure.
也许他们离开了
well, maybe they left.
没这么好运  他们就在我们后边
no such luck. they're right behind us.
战斗机正在朝我们的位置驶来
fighters, closing in on our position.
你那里进展怎么样了
how's it going down there?
再给我点儿时间
look, just give me a second!
罗德尼
rodney...
好了  现在试一试
okay, try it now.
好了  我搞定了
that's it, i've got it!
启动  启动  启动
go, go, go, go, go, go!
谢帕德
sheppard...
我们现在情况如何
how we doing?
他们紧咬着我们不放
they're gaining on us.
我们能再快点儿吗
can you get us more speed?
根本没有可能
there's not a chance!
我好不容易才让这鬼东西工作
look, i've barely got this thing working as it is!
如果我们继续加大功率
if we tax it any more,
整个系统会崩溃的
we're going to blow the whole system!
这样的话我们麻烦大了
then we've got a real problem.
他们进入攻击射程
they're in weapons range.
反击
return fire.
我正努力去做
i'm trying.
冷静点儿伙计  这些按钮与你无仇
easy, chewie, those buttons are your friends.
继续努力
just keep trying.
我很努力了
i'm trying!
这下好了  亚光速器这次彻底坏掉了
that's it, sublights are gone for good this time!
那是什么鬼东西
what the hell was that?
f-302s
f-302s.
是亚特兰蒂斯
it's atlantis.
发生了什么
what's happening?
我们得到火力援助了
looks like we're getting some help from some friends.
看来我们选对了盟友
guess we bet on the right side after all.
代达罗斯号  这是中校约翰·谢帕德
daedalus , this is lt. colonel john sheppard.
收到请讲
do you read?
代达罗斯号  收到请讲
daedalus, do you read?
收到  这里是代达罗斯号
yeah,  daedalus. uh, this is  daedalus .
请讲
come in.
谁  这是谁
who... who is this?
说来话长
it's a long story.
不管你是谁  当你摧毁他们主武器的时候
well, whoever you are, you saved our asses
救了我们一把
when you took out their main weapons.
我想至少我们可以礼尚往来
figured the least we could do is return the favor.
笑纳了
much appreciated.
谢帕德
uh, sheppard...
该死
oh, crap.
刚才的很抱歉
sorry about that.
有一个逃脱了
one of 'em got through.
不过射击的挺漂亮的
nice shooting, though.
谢谢
oh, thanks.
好了  看起来这是他们最后一个了
all right, looks like that's the last of them.
现在怎么办
so, uh... so, what happens now?
我们走我们自己的
well, we go our own ways.
就这样?
just like that?
就这样
pretty much.
问题是
well, the thing is, uh,
我们有些困惑
we do have a few questions.
我们所熟知的代达罗斯号两年前与复制人的战斗中
see, the  daedalus we know was destroyed two years ago
已经被摧毁了
in a battle with the replicators.
很遗憾听到这个消息
sorry to hear that,
但是这并不是完全意义上的代达罗斯号
but this isn't exactly our  daedalus .
我们只是暂时借用一下
we're just borrowing it for a while.
好吧  我现在完全云里雾里
okay, i have no idea what that means.
如我所讲  这故事说来话长
like i said, it's a long story.
好吧  代达罗斯号  祝你好运
all right,  daedalus , good luck.
谢谢
thank you, colonel,
最后一件事情
and one last thing,
遇到你很愉快
it's been a pleasure.
很显然  你有一身正气
you're obviously a man of great integrity,
而且是一名负责的指挥官
and a dedicated commander,
并且是一名优秀的飞行员
and a very skilled pilot.
很有意思
well, that's funny.
我也想这样评价你
i was going to say the same to you.
好的
all right.
异族飞船离开了
the alien ship's gone.
我读取到了一个没有能源显示的星球
i'm reading a planet with no energy signatures.
这是我们跃迁到达的第一个时空
it's the first reality we jumped to.
再来一个  我们就可以回家了
one more, and we're home.
我们现在去停泊舱
let's get down to the hangar bay.
好的
all right...
我中枪了
i got shot!
我以为他们都被干掉了
i thought we got 'em all.
显然没有处理干净
apparently not.
你认为附近还有他们的人吗
think there's any more of them?
我们没空去搜寻了
we're not waiting around to find out.
快跑  快跑  快跑
move, move, move!
爆炸造成了船体裂缝
the explosion's caused a hull breech.
所有区域压强下降
whole sections have been de-pressurized,
包括停泊舱
including the hangar bay!
我们的飞船没了!
we just lost the jumpers!
罗德尼  我们该去往下一站了
our stop is coming up, rodney.
是时候弃舰了
it's time to get off this train.
但是根本没有出口哇
look, there's no way off.
一旦我们跃迁进入自己的时空
once we jump into our own reality,
亚特兰蒂斯会探测到我们的
atlantis will detect us,
然后我们可以发出求救信号
and they will send help.
为了躲避战斗机  我们偏离了预定轨道
we broke orbit to get away from the fighters, remember?
我们按照自己的路径
look, we carry our momentum
还有空间中的相对坐标
and relative position in space
从一个空间穿梭到另一个
from one reality to the next.
也就是说  下一次跃迁
which means, by the time we next jump,
我们可能会偏离预定位置几百万公里
we're going to be, like, half a million kilometers out.
他们根本无法及时找到我们
they're never going to get to us in time!
我们有C-4炸药
we got c-4.
我们等待机会回去  然后炸掉推进器
we wait till we get back, then we blow the drive.
也许可行
that could work,
但也只能在时空连续空间内炸个小洞
or it could tear a hole in the space-time continuum
不但害死我们自己
not only killing us
甚至摧毁整个太阳系
but destroying the entire solar system!
我们最好快点儿想个法子
well, we'd better think of something fast.
屏幕上再次出现了呼救信号
another contact just appeared on our screens.
是不是代达罗斯号发出的?
was it the  daedalus ?
不可能  距离太远根本无法通信
no, they're too far out for us to get i.f.f.
那么试一试亚空间通信
well, try subspace.
谢帕德中校  收到请回答
colonel sheppard, do you read?
谢帕德中校  我是罗恩少校
colonel sheppard, this is major lorne,
收到请讲
do you read?
他们是不是超空间飞行了
was there a hyperspace window?
长官  没有
no, sir.
他们只是突然间冒出来了
they just appeared out of nowhere.
那么  一定是他们
well, it's got to be them.
叫伍尔希先生注意  博士你跟我来
alert mr. woolsey. doc, you're with me.
我们走  快点儿
let's go, come on.
好了  我们现在应该在呼叫范围内了
all right, we should be within radio range.
谢帕德中校  请讲
colonel sheppard, come in.
麦凯博士  我是罗恩少校
dr. mckay, this is major lorne.
收到请讲
do you read?
干扰太大了
there's too much interference.
我截获了某种能量信号
i'm picking up some kind of energy reading.
成尖峰状
it's spiking.
到底发生了什么
what the hell just happened?
他们突然消失了
they disappeared.
你在说什么
what are you talking about?
他们就这样消失了
well... they're just gone.
等一下
oh, wait a minute.
我截取到4个生命迹象
i'm picking up four lifesigns.
好的  哪里
okay, where?
就在前边
dead ahead.
谢帕德中校  是你吗
colonel sheppard, is that you?
少校
major...
很高兴你找到我们
nice of you to stop by.
这附近连个鬼影就见不到
kind of hard to get a cab in this neighborhood.
长官  收到
yes, sir.
推进器损坏以前
how many jumps
还可以进行几次时空跃迁
you think that drive has left in it before it burns out?
最多六次
half a dozen, tops.
6次后就失效了
then it'll be completely inert.
好的
good.
我可不希望有人跟我们一样
i'd hate to think of somebody else
困在那个鬼地方
getting trapped inside that thing like we did.
事实上  我一直在想  没错
actually, you know,i've been thinking about that. now, true,
导航系统因为故障无法启动
the navigation system was flawed to start,
但是推进器的基本原理
but the basic principles of the drive
是合乎常理的
are fundamentally sound--
行了  罗德尼
forget it, rodney.
我保留了相关的数据
i've saved the relevant data.
局部改进一下  我就可以
minor adjustments, and i should be able to
让这东西开始工作了
have this thing up and running--
我说了别倒腾这东西了
i said forget it.
看看谁来了
hey, look who's here.
罗德尼  你的肩膀怎么样了
how's your shoulder, rodney?
伤的挺重
uh, it's pretty bad,
但是现在好了些  谢谢了
but, you know, better, thanks.
有劲儿抱抱他吗
is it well enough to hold him?
说真的吗
really?
别把他摔了
don't drop him.
谢谢
thank you.
瞧瞧  小家伙
hey there, little guy.
我想他喜欢我
i think he likes me.
看起来很配
it suits you.
你也这么认为
you think so?
我想有一天你会成为一个伟大的父亲
i think you'll make an excellent father someday.
我一生中目睹了无数可怕的事情
i've seen a lot of scary things in my time,
但是这个尤为吓人
but that thought scares me the most.
你想...
do you want to, um...
我想是的
i think so.
给你  小心点儿
there you go, watch out...
好的
right.